Ivan Palmegiani

ivan.palmegiani@gmail.com | LinkedIn Account | GitHub Account

Address and phone number available on request



Profile

Researcher with strong analytical mindset and very good organization skills. Advanced technical capabilities developed over 5+ years working experience, and intensive training. Excellent communication skills. Team worker, also able to take charge of tasks individually. Highly motivated and positive towards challenges. Solution oriented and careful about details. Constructive critical thinker. Curious and eager to learn.

Expertise

R coding | Python programming | Relational (geo)databases - MySQL and PostGreSQL | Geographic Information Systems - QGIS | Geodata analyses and modelling | Remote sensing | Time series analyses and forecast | Machine Learning (ML) | Data visualization | Data reporting | Research | Content writing

Languages

English - IELTS certification level C1 • German - TELC certification level B1 • Italian - mother tongue • Spanish - fluent • Portuguese - fluent

Professional Experience

Independent Researcher | Environmental Data Scientist, Nov 2019 - Present

Main clients: SmartCloudFarming GmgH (DE) | | EarthRatings UG (DE) | University of Primorska (SI) Services: Spatial analyses and modelling - Geodatabase management - Geodata query - Remote sensing - Exploratory data analyses (EDA) - Feature Engineering - ML - Bibliographic research and reporting - Content crafting for funding applications and marketing - Consulting for nature conservation projects.

PhD Candidate, May 2014 - Jun. 2018 | **Research Assistant**, Apr. 2013 - Sept. 2013 | IZW - Leibniz Institute for Zoo and Wildlife Research (DE)

Main goal: Investigating the social system of the cheetah in central Namibia by the analysis of individual movement patterns and utilization of space.

- Collected and processed time series of geo-referenced data from satellite telemetry.
- Performed spatial and movement analyses on tracking data.
- Explored data and modelled environmental dynamics with linear and nonlinear regression models.
- Collected and analyzed presence-absence data via camera-trap surveys.
- Designed and maintained online and offline (geo)databases.
- Provided insights to stakeholders, team members, and scientific audiences through public talks, data reporting and visualization.

- Coordinated data collection in the field, supervised volunteers.
- Organized scientific symposia.

Research Assistant, Dec. 2012 - Feb. 2013 | Research Technician, Feb. 2012 - Nov. 2012

CIBIO - Research Center in Biodiversity and Genetic Resources (PT)

Main goal: Investigating the spatial ecology of endangered wildlife species in the Iberian peninsula (Portugal and Spain).

- Collected and analyzed satellite telemetry and geo-referenced environmental data.
- Explored and modelled species distribution in relation to environmental variables using linear and nonlinear regression models.
- Designed and maintained relational (geo)databases.
- Provided insights to stake-holders, team members, and scientific audiences through public talks, data reporting and visualization.

Research Technician, Nov. 2010 - Nov. 2011

Department of Zoology and Evolutionary Genetics, University of Sassari (IT)

Main goal: Investigate spatial distribution, abundance and reproductive success of wolves in central Italy.

- · Collected geo-referenced environmental data.
- Collected and analyzed bio-acoustic data.
- Collected and analyzed presence-absence data via camera-trap surveys.

Education

Master of Science (MSc), Jul. 2010

Environmental Sciences and Natural Resources Management, University of Sassari. Grade: 110/110 cum Laude Environmental modelling, statistical inference, advanced statistical theory, zoocenosis and wildlife conservation, wildlife management, genetics, plant conservation, environmental economics, systems ecology, landscape ecology, regional geology, sedimentology.

Hobbies and interests

Outdoor sports and activities such as climbing, bouldering, hiking, biking, canoeing, camping • Indoor gardening • Urban agriculture • DIY and Handicraft • Music and Arts • Cooking